# **Benjamin Arrants**

**Business Analyst** 

Seattle, Washington, United States□ 206-708-3565

benarrants@gmail.com

% linkedin.com/in/benjamin-arrants

https://benarrants.github.io/

# **Projects**

# **Staffing Distribution**

Strategically assigned key medical staff ahead of the flu season using Excel VLOOKUP, pivot tables, and hypothesis testing, with Tableau (for data visualization). <u>Tableau</u> Story

#### **Market Research**

Conducted analysis to identify opportunities for a movie rental shop's transition to an online service using SQL queries, subqueries, and common table expressions, Excel for reporting, and Tableau visualizations. Github

### **Ecommerce Buying Patterns**

Examined 30+ million data entries to identify the correlation between customer buying behavior and ecommerce marketing strategy doing cleaning, wrangling, and merging all in Jupyter Python, with Excel for reporting. Github

#### **Technical Skills**

- Excel
- PowerPoint
- Tableau
- SQL
- Python

# **SUMMARY**

A Business Analyst with experience in Customer Success, having an impressive track record of devising and implementing strategies and procedures that deliver results regarding employee productivity and customer experience. Improve processes and workflow through the discovery of compelling insights via comprehensive data reporting and engaging visualization.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# OfferUp, Bellevue, Washington

Customer Success Implementation Specialist

2020 - 2022

- Onboarded customer accounts for auto dealers to get their vehicles visible to front-end consumers.
- Developed capable skills in troubleshooting issues, either within the onboarding process or impacting existing customers.
- Tested and reported problems with processes or products on SaaS systems and wrote process documentation that was published internally for employees.
- Analyzed weekly data for the team and sent summaries regarding overall team performance WoW.
- Worked cross-functionally by creating reports and dashboards to improve team onboarding processes for increased efficiency.

**Business Development Representative** 

2019-2020

- Worked during the initial launch of the Autos Concierge program answering customer chats on behalf of auto dealer clients.
- Mentored team members as they joined the growing service.
- Attained proficient capabilities using SaaS systems, honed efficient communication capabilities, and fostered de-escalation skills.

#### Keller Supply Company, Lynnwood and Monroe, Washington

Warehouse Associate

2014-2018

- Sourced inventory from stock to expedite customer will-call orders, fulfill truck deliveries and ship stock as requested to other branches.
- Impeccable inventory management and organization.
- Monroe Branch was awarded for inventory count accuracy.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **Data Analytics Certificate**

2023

CareerFoundry, Berlin, Germany

## Western Washington University, Bachelor of Arts

2014-2018

Political Science, Philosophy, and Economics